{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Capon ","incorrectAnswers":["Bodice","Prized Cock","Lode"],"question":"What name is given to a cockerel that is castrated and fattened for the table?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thomas Jefferson","incorrectAnswers":["George Washington","Abraham Lincoln","Ronald Reagan"],"question":"Which influential historical person was the 3rd President of the USA and the principle author of the US Declaration of Independence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Tax evasion","incorrectAnswers":["Murder","Fraud","Bribery"],"question":"Gangster Al Capone, boss of the Chicago underworld, was finally jailed for 11 years for what crime?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The African Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Midnight Cowboy","Raiders of the Lost Ark","Ghost"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Rose Sayer'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gladiator","incorrectAnswers":["Chocolat","Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon","Erin Brockovich"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2000?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Butterfly","incorrectAnswers":["Musical Youth","New Radicals","Twisted Sister"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1968 with In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Panama","Nepal"],"question":"In which country is grappa a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bucharest","incorrectAnswers":["Sarajevo","Bratislava","Vientiane"],"question":"What is the capital city of Romania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","Spain","Netherlands"],"question":"Which European nation unified the three areas under its control into a unified Vietnam in the 1880s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Madame Butterfly","incorrectAnswers":["Swan Lake","HMS Pinafore","Candide"],"question":"In what opera would you find Lt. Pinkerton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Korean War","incorrectAnswers":["The Vietnam War","World War II","The Spanish Civil War"],"question":"In what war did jet fighters first battle each other?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Poland","Switzerland"],"question":"Berlin is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tbilisi","incorrectAnswers":["Kutaisi","Batumi","Telavi"],"question":"What is the capital of Georgia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Mauritius","Fiji","Qatar"],"question":"Bangkok is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\"","\"I have nipples Greg. Could you milk me?\"","\"Elementary, my dear Watson.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Godfather'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cream","incorrectAnswers":["Jefferson Airplane","Stereolab","Simply Red"],"question":"Which band included the iconic guitarist Eric Clapton?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Google Chrome","incorrectAnswers":["Mozilla Firefox","Microsoft Edge","Safari"],"question":"As of 2023, what is the most used web browser?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A full house","incorrectAnswers":["A flush","A straight","Three of a kind"],"question":"What is the name of the poker hand that consists of three cards of one rank and two cards of another rank?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mont Blanc ","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Etna","Elbrus","Grossglockner"],"question":"What Is The Highest Mountain In The Alps?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Spanish imitation of an Aztec word ","incorrectAnswers":["A King of Mali","A town in Brazil","Cockney rhyming slang"],"question":"How did chocolate get its name?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Oasis","Led Zeppelin","The Clash"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Hey Jude'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I see dead people.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I have had it with these mother—— snakes on this mother—— plane!\"","\"I have nipples Greg. Could you milk me?\"","\"You talking to me?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Sixth Sense'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Ecuador","Suriname"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Argentina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Orange Juice ","incorrectAnswers":["Lemon Juice","Pineapple Juice","Apple Juice"],"question":"With what is champagne mixed to produce `Buck's Fizz'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vascular systems","incorrectAnswers":["Puzzles","Wave motions","The records of tree rings"],"question":"What is Angiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"LXIX","incorrectAnswers":["CXIX","LIXX","CIXX"],"question":"How do you write 69 in Roman numerals?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Little Boy","incorrectAnswers":["Fat Man","Trinity","Hiroshima"],"question":"What was the name of the first atomic bomb used in combat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gérard Depardieu","incorrectAnswers":["Kevin Costner","Shah Rukh Khan","Jack Nicholson"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Life of Pi and La Vie en Rose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ladies Love Cool James","incorrectAnswers":["Live Laugh Cool Jokes","Little Lean Cool Jams","Look Look Cool Jives"],"question":"What does LL Cool J.'s name stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Lacrosse","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Football","Baseball"],"question":"What sport, played with sticks with pouches at the end, was called 'Baggataway' by Native Americans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azan","incorrectAnswers":["Adhan","Niqāb","Iqama"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic call to prayer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Liquid assets","incorrectAnswers":["Leverage","Private equity","Diverse holdings"],"question":"What is the term for the part of a financial portfolio that can be turned into cash quickly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Hockey","incorrectAnswers":["Athletics","Figure skating","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Dhyan Chand associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gone with the Wind","incorrectAnswers":["The Fall of the King","All Quiet on the Western Front","A Tale of Two Cities"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Scarlett O’Hara was not beautiful, but men seldom realized it when caught by her charm as the Tarleton twins were.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1975","incorrectAnswers":["1965","1970","1980"],"question":"Jaws was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flower","incorrectAnswers":["Star","Microchip","Spider"],"question":"Corolla, filament and stigma are parts of a what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Earth","incorrectAnswers":["Wood","Metal","Rock"],"question":"What type of material is loam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lucky Jim","incorrectAnswers":["Of Mice and Men","Love in the Time of Cholera","In Our Time"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Jim Dixon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"George Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Hedges","Norman Jones","Paul Starkley"],"question":"Who was known as 'the fifth Beatle', producing a great deal of The Beatles' music?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dhaka","incorrectAnswers":["Busan","Petaling Jaya","Phnom Penh"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Bangladesh?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Errol Flynn","incorrectAnswers":["Sidney Poitier","Robert Mitchum","Clint Eastwood"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Robin Hood in The Adventures of Robin Hood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mamma Mia!","incorrectAnswers":["Grease","West Side Story","Les Misérables"],"question":"Which popular musical features the music of ABBA?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia and Herzegovina","Albania","Bulgaria"],"question":"Valencia is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Apollo 11","incorrectAnswers":["Sputnik 1","Voyager 1","Gemini 6"],"question":"What is the name of the first spacecraft to land on the moon?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Henry Treece","Antoine de Saint-Exupery","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Ugly Duckling\" and \"The Emperor's New Clothes\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"One Hundred Years of Solitude","incorrectAnswers":["The Sound and the Fury","Under the Volcano","The English Patient"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Aureliano Buendia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Origami","incorrectAnswers":["Kabuki","Kintsugi","Kokeshi"],"question":"What is the name of the traditional Japanese art of paper folding?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Phoenix","incorrectAnswers":["The Roc","The Harpy","The Siren"],"question":"What is the name of the mythical bird that dies in a fire and is reborn from its own ashes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Breaking Bad","incorrectAnswers":["SpongeBob Squarepants","Brooklyn 99","American Vandals"],"question":"In which popular American TV series would you find the character Jesse Pinkman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Egg","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Soured Cream","Milk"],"question":"What Is The Principle Ingredient Of Mayonnaise?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mulligan","incorrectAnswers":["Hogan","Palmer","Nicklaus"],"question":"What is the name of the type of shot in golf, used informally to allow a player after a shot goes wrong due to bad luck?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1805","incorrectAnswers":["1863","1911","1840"],"question":"In Which Year Was The Battle Of Trafalgar Fought?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Radioactivity","incorrectAnswers":["Oscillations","Snowfall","Planetary Orbits"],"question":"What is measured by a Geiger counter","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Art Nouveau","Romanticism","Cubism"],"question":"The Sistine Chapel ceiling painting by Michelangelo is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Maya Angelou","Amiri Baraka","Alan Bennett"],"question":"Who wrote the play \"The Mousetrap\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","Italy","Uruguay"],"question":"Which country won the 1954 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Switzerland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","Faroe Islands","Iran"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Green with a yellow diamond in the center with a blue celestial globe.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Orson Welles","incorrectAnswers":["James Stewart","Humphrey Bogart","John Belushi"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Harry Lime in The Third Man?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Perrault","incorrectAnswers":["Hans Christian Andersen","André Gide","Prosper Mérimée"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Puss in Boots'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tupac Shakur","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Ludacris","Nas"],"question":"Which American rapper released the album 'All Eyez on Me'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After a mathematician accepts secret work in cryptography, his life takes a turn for the nightmarish.","incorrectAnswers":["POWs are forced to build a railway, not knowing that allies are planning to destroy it.","The final secretary for Adolf Hitler tells of the Nazi dictator's final days.","The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie A Beautiful Mind?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Carrie'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Russia","Germany"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Agra Fort?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Polycrates","incorrectAnswers":["Minos","Hercules","Perseus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who ruled over the island of Samos?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Six Nations","incorrectAnswers":["The Open Championship","The FINA World Championships","The Hopman Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Rugby competition?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Campanelle","incorrectAnswers":["Macaroni","Rigatoni","Orecchiette"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Little bells'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lego","incorrectAnswers":["Playmobil","Nintendo","Mattel"],"question":"Which company, with a name formed by contracting the Danish words for 'play well', was founded by carpenter Ole Kristiansen in 1932?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The end of human existence","incorrectAnswers":["Wounds and injuries caused by accidents","Dreams","Plants"],"question":"What is eschatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mod","incorrectAnswers":["Rocker","Hippie","Goth"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion subculture that originated in London in the late 1950s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["Six","Three","Five"],"question":"How many seams are there on a football (American)?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Lawrence","incorrectAnswers":["Jessica Chastain","Emmanuelle Riva","Quvenzhané Wallis"],"question":"Who won the 2012 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Tiffany in Silver Linings Playbook?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bell pepper","incorrectAnswers":["Jalapeno pepper","Habanero pepper","Serrano pepper"],"question":"Which sweet pepper is named for its shape and is commonly used in salads?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Operation","incorrectAnswers":["Surgery","Trauma Center","ER"],"question":"Which game  involves a patient called Cavity Sam, from whom players must remove objects using a pair of tweezers?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Foundation’s Edge'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cygnet","incorrectAnswers":["A Spiderling","A Colt","A Swanling"],"question":"A young swan is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Butch Cassidy","incorrectAnswers":["Billy the Kid","Jesse James","Calamity Jane"],"question":"Who led the Wild Bunch and conducted the first major train robbery near Wilcox, Wyoming, on June 2nd, 1899?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Morgan Freeman","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Lee","Liam Neeson","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Batman Begins and Lucy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Giraffe","incorrectAnswers":["Llama","Kangaroo","Komodo Dragon"],"question":"As what is a camelopard also known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Sliver'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is farfalle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The King's Speech","incorrectAnswers":["Black Swan","The Fighter","Inception"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2010?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Croatia","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Senegal","Ireland"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Kingdom of the Netherlands","Belgium","France"],"question":"Which of these countries borders United Kingdom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yemen ","incorrectAnswers":["Kuwait","Qatar","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"Which country at the southern tip of the Arabian Peninsula was previously known as Aden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ghost","incorrectAnswers":["Apocalypse Now","Blue Velvet","Terms of Endearment"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Oda Mae Brown'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"East and West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["North and South Korea","Vietnam and Cambodia","North & South Sudan"],"question":"Which two countries agreed to reunite on February 13th, 1989?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Denmark","Finland"],"question":"In which country is pisco a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kahlua ","incorrectAnswers":["Advocaat","Baileys","Limoncello"],"question":"White Russian Cocktails Are Made From Milk, Vodka And _______","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Percussion","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a violin?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marie Antoinette","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine the Great","Queen Victoria","Elizabeth I"],"question":"Which French queen led a fashion revolution in 1783 by wearing a strikingly simple white muslin dress?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Yellow","Red"],"question":"What color are Smurfs?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romeo and Juliet","incorrectAnswers":["Othello","Hamlet","King Lear"],"question":"What shakespearean play features the line: \"A plague on both your houses\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Wagner","incorrectAnswers":["Newman","Hoffman","Schneider"],"question":"Who wrote the opera \"The Flying Dutchman\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Pan American Highway","incorrectAnswers":["Route 1","The Transcontinental Road","Christopher Columbus Road"],"question":"Which Road Runs From Alaska To Chile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ralph Fiennes","incorrectAnswers":["Brian Cox","Mark Wahlberg","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Harry Potter and Schindler's List?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Communist Party","incorrectAnswers":["The Castro Party","The Republican Party","The Socialist Party"],"question":"Which party has a majority in Cuba's National Assembly of People's Power?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","John Lennon","Stevie Wonder"],"question":"Who was Paul McCartney's duet partner on the 1983 hit 'Say Say Say'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Gorbachev","incorrectAnswers":["Boris Yeltsin","Vladimir Lenin","Josef Stalin"],"question":"Who resigned as Russian Premier on Christmas day 1991?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Yellow","Red"],"question":" What colour is the flesh of an avocado?","difficulty":"easy"},